<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Mehmet Ali Erturk</title>
        <link>http://localhost:59522/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Mehmet Ali Erturk</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 21:57:40 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:59522/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>My Reflections on Reading</title>
    <link>http://localhost:59522/posts/my-reflect%C4%B1ons-on-reading/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>merturk</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:59522/posts/my-reflect%C4%B1ons-on-reading/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I started to share scientific papers related to my interests that could be informative, mostly on digital twins, IoT, 5G/6G networks, and cybersecurity. Except for scientific content (papers, book chapters, reviews, etc.), I plan my reading each year and try to stick to the plan to hit my annual goals. This year, I barely achieved half of the books I planned to read the previous year.</p>
<p>I recently read a book titled The Art of Laziness: Overcome Procrastination &amp; Improve Your Productivity. The book is concise and has a suitable length, discussing its points with just the right amount of content — neither too much nor too little. Here are my main takeaways from the book: First is Cyril Northcote Parkinson’s Law, which states that “work expands to fill the time available for its completion.” This means that the amount of work we’ll do tends to increase to fill the time we give ourselves. Another key point is that “all you need are two things: a pen and paper.” I still find it effective to use a pen or pencil and paper to jot down my thoughts. This method works well for me, and I plan to continue using it. Lastly, I want to mention the Pygmalion Effect, which is a psychological phenomenon where you tend to work harder when you see yourself as a diligent person.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Digital Twins Selected Reading: Predictive Modeling in Wind Turbines</title>
    <link>http://localhost:59522/posts/dt-wind-turbines/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>merturk</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:59522/posts/dt-wind-turbines/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Digital Twin (DT) is a technology that creates a virtual replica of physical entities and processes for real-time analysis. DT approach enables what-if analysis over with high accuracy models that classic simulations cannot handle.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png" title="Digital Twin Arch" data-thumbnail="/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Digital Twin Arch</h2><p>Digital Twin Arch</p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Digital Twin Arch</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>IoT (Internet of Things) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) are crucial technologies that enable Digital Twin (DT) systems. In DT, a physical asset is replicated in real-time through two-way communication channels, while virtual models represent the asset virtually. AI and Machine Learning analyze the data generated by the virtual models.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
