<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reading on Mehmet Ali Erturk</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/categories/reading/</link><description>Recent content in Reading on Mehmet Ali Erturk</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 12:16:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mehmetalierturk.com/categories/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stirling Castle</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/stirling-castle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 17:04:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/stirling-castle/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stirling Castle is one of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s iconic castles, offering a spectacular view of the Stirling area. Built in the 1500s, the castle has played a significant role throughout &lt;a href="https://www.historicenvironment.scot/visit-a-place/places/stirling-castle/history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">history&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It served as a royal residence during that time and is easily accessible from Edinburgh. With attractions such as the Royal Palace, the Great Hall, and beautiful gardens, it is definitely worth a &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/merturk/albums/72177720327359544/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">visit&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;a class="lightgallery" href="https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/stirling-castle/stirling1.jpg" title="Stirling Castle" data-thumbnail="/posts/stirling-castle/stirling1.jpg" data-sub-html="&lt;h2>Stirling Castle&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Stirling Castle&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unexpected Role of Punch Cards in Textile Production</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/jacquard-loom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 12:46:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/jacquard-loom/</guid><description>&lt;p>I always thought punch cards were used solely for programming early computers, but I recently discovered that this is not the case. During my visit to the National Museum of Scotland, I encountered the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jacquard_machine" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Jacquard loom&lt;/a>, invented by French weaver Joseph-Marie Jacquard in 1804. I learned that this production of patterned textiles was automated using punch cards, demonstrating their use as far back as the 1800s. I was surprised to find out about this historical application of punch cards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple RSA Encryption with Mathematica</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/rsa-example/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 18:57:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/rsa-example/</guid><description>&lt;p>RSA is a widely used public-key algorithm that relies on a pair of keys — a public key (e) for encryption and a private key (d) for decryption. More information can be found on &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSA_cryptosystem" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Wikipedia&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.cryptography-textbook.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Understanding Cryptography Textbook&lt;/a>. For testing purposes and to explore how Mathematica handles RSA encryption, I would like to write a small script that encrypts and decrypts data using RSA with small numbers. You can download Mathamatica &lt;a href="https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/rsa-example/RSAExample.nb" rel="">notebook&lt;/a> and also sample &lt;a href="./RSAExample.nb.pdf" rel="">output&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reading Materials</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/useful-info/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 17:57:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/useful-info/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have gathered useful content from various sources and grouped it together for easy reference in &lt;a href="https://mehmetalierturk.com/resources/index.html" title="resources" rel="">resources&lt;/a> section.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Everyday Fountain Pen Ink</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/f-ink/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 12:16:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/f-ink/</guid><description>&lt;p>I continue to stay analog in the digital world, mainly using pen and paper. Besides pencils, I also like to use fountain pens (as well as other types of roller pens). I have tried many inks so far, and Parker Blue-Black QUINK Ink ( &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Parker-Quink-57ml-Bottle-Permanent/dp/B000J61TIM?th=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Amazon Link&lt;/a>) is the best in terms of color, smoothness, and price tag. The deep, rich tone of blue-black provides an elegance that enhances my writing, making even the most everyday notes and draft ideas special.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Reflections on Reading</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/my-reflect%C4%B1ons-on-reading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/my-reflect%C4%B1ons-on-reading/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I started to share scientific papers related to my interests that could be informative, mostly on digital twins, IoT, 5G/6G networks, and cybersecurity. Except for scientific content (papers, book chapters, reviews, etc.), I plan my reading each year and try to stick to the plan to hit my annual goals. This year, I barely achieved half of the books I planned to read the previous year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recently read a book titled The Art of Laziness: Overcome Procrastination &amp;amp; Improve Your Productivity. The book is concise and has a suitable length, discussing its points with just the right amount of content — neither too much nor too little. Here are my main takeaways from the book: First is Cyril Northcote Parkinson’s Law, which states that “work expands to fill the time available for its completion.” This means that the amount of work we’ll do tends to increase to fill the time we give ourselves. Another key point is that “all you need are two things: a pen and paper.” I still find it effective to use a pen or pencil and paper to jot down my thoughts. This method works well for me, and I plan to continue using it. Lastly, I want to mention the Pygmalion Effect, which is a psychological phenomenon where you tend to work harder when you see yourself as a diligent person.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Digital Twins Selected Reading: Predictive Modeling in Wind Turbines</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/dt-wind-turbines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/dt-wind-turbines/</guid><description>&lt;p>Digital Twin (DT) is a technology that creates a virtual replica of physical entities and processes for real-time analysis. DT approach enables what-if analysis over with high accuracy models that classic simulations cannot handle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;a class="lightgallery" href="https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png" title="Digital Twin Arch" data-thumbnail="/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png" data-sub-html="&lt;h2>Digital Twin Arch&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Digital Twin Arch&lt;/p>">
 &lt;img
 class="lazyload"
 src="https://mehmetalierturk.com/svg/loading.min.svg"
 data-src="https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png"
 data-srcset="https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png, https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png 1.5x, https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png 2x"
 data-sizes="auto"
 alt="/posts/dt-wind-turbines/dt.png" width="1400" height="651" />
 &lt;/a>&lt;figcaption class="image-caption">Digital Twin Arch&lt;/figcaption>
 &lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IoT (Internet of Things) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) are crucial technologies that enable Digital Twin (DT) systems. In DT, a physical asset is replicated in real-time through two-way communication channels, while virtual models represent the asset virtually. AI and Machine Learning analyze the data generated by the virtual models.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Graph Signal Processing (GSP)</title><link>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/gsp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://mehmetalierturk.com/posts/gsp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Graph Signal Processing (GSP) is a mathematical framework that extends discrete signal processing (DSP) tools such as filtering and signal decomposition to graph data structures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Graph Signal Processing is suitable for scenarios where data don’t have a regular pattern or cannot be represented as time series signals. In such scenarios, modeling through graph structures can exploit signal-processing tasks on complex structures through GSP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>GSP can be applied to network structures such as sensor, social, and biological networks. As well as image processing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>